I don't think the language, this country's history is complicated, is useful.
Venezuela has a complicated history.
Idon has a complicated history.
Israel has a complicated history, right?
That so often is like this language to separate folks from involving themselves in understanding.
And let me also say, every nation has a complicated history.
The complications that you're talking about may have happened at a different time frame than the present recent 100 years.
However, nationhood, countryhood is complicated because it's unnatural.
Yeah, it's not supposed to be the way it is, right?
But to be honest, the context of complication is also, I feel like, a misapplication.
Because what makes it complicated?
That there's many things that took place?
That there's a lot of different people that were affected in different ways?
We can't keep calling that complicated.
What that is, is just dense, robust.
Because the word complicated turns people away from thinking they can try to grasp it.
You know, it's like taxes, how they make taxes like really complicated for no reason.
To make sure that there's an entire industry around doing taxes.
Unnecessary.
And I'm not saying that everyone can.
But what I'm saying is that we need to encourage people to want to learn.
And stop siloing things into spaces that make people feel like they are not able to.
That is what Zionists successfully did for a long time with Israel.
Then you go in and you're like, oh, this isn't complicated at all.
This is two plus two equals colonialism.
So, yes, there might be like a very storied history of events.
But at the crux, oftentimes it's very basic.
And I want us to start understanding ourselves as part of a globe.
Because we are already seen as a globe to be stolen from.
We are already seen as an earth of people to be used as resources.
So we need to see ourselves as all interconnected so that we can see ourselves as an earth of people to resist.
And if we keep pushing people away by saying, but you wouldn't understand what happened over here.
We're never going to get there.
And yes.
These are Palestine cats.